ANDREW COBB

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I previously graduated from Northumbria University as a Graduate of BSC(Hons) Computer Science with Games Development with First Class Honours and I am currently employed at OneAdvanced, one of the UK's leading software companies as a Senior Support Consultant. I have worked in several positions since leaving my studies as shown below and have developed a wide range of skills and experience during that time that I aim to progress further in my next role.

KEY SKILLS

- Boundless Critical thinking & problem-solving skills gained from both my time in education and several job sectors.
- Excellent Communication & teamworking skills obtained from my earlier experience in the Gateshead Police Cadets and enhanced with further experience.
- Initiative-taking and enthusiastic within all earlier roles with the drive to learn and better myself.
- Notable control of time management and task prioritisation displayed during my studies and work, exhibiting my ability to be both a flexible and dependable member of a team.
- Vital experience gained from working in both small and large teams with recently gained leadership and project management experience.
- Experience in a senior position within a team, providing mentorship and the transferring of skills and knowledge due to my drive to better my team and myself improving the quality of service provided and improving customer relations.
- Ability to collaborate with different teams and departments with experience in dealing with both customer escalations, urgent queries and even in larger scenarios such as back to green plans.

KEY EXPERIENCE

- Programming Languages: HTML5 & CSS (6+ Years), SQL (2+ Years),
 PHP (3+ Years), Java (4+ Years), JavaScript (3+ Years), C# (3+ Years),
 C++ (3+ Years), PROLOG(1 Year), .NET(1 Year)
- Software: Microsoft Office (10+ Years), Adobe Software (10+ Years), Unreal Engine (5+ Years), Unity (4+ Years), Visual Studio (4+ Years), PowerShell (1 Year)
- Experience in Roles: Project Leader, Level Designer, Gameplay Programmer, UI Programmer, AI Programmer, Level Designer, Game Designer, Story Writer, Game Artist, Technical Analyst/Support Consultant, Senior Technical Analyst/Support consultant.

CONTACT

- **** 07572464167
- ✓ andrew-cobb@outlook.com
- Gateshead, United Kingdom
- https://cobbinho97.github.io/github-portfolio/

EDUCATION

2016-2020

NORTHUMBRIA UNIVERSITY

 BSC (hons)Computer Science with Games Development – 1st Class Honours

Foundation Year

 Modules: Digital Technologies, Introduction to Information Systems, Code Wrangling for Beginners, Exploring the Digital Society

Year 1

Modules: Procedural Programming,
 Computing Fundamentals, Object Oriented
 Programming, Systems Analysis, Relational
 Databases, Web Technologies

Year 2

Modules: Web Programming, Program
 Design and Development, Human
 Computer Interaction, Software
 Engineering Practice, Intelligent Systems,
 Computer Networks, Security and
 Operating System

Year 3

 Modules: Individual Computing Project, Computer Graphics and Animation, Games Design, Team Project and Professionalism, Software Architecture for Games

2014-2016

GATESHEAD COLLEGE

 BTEC Extended Diploma with Games Development - DMM

2008-2013

CARDINAL HUME CATHOLIC SCHOOL

 9 GCSE's A – C including Maths and English

- Notable Projects: Upon request I can provide the following as proof of creation:
 - o Procedural Generation (Procedural Generation of a 3D Environment Maze with each reinitialisation).
 - o Creation of an Android-like Game (Created using Visual Studio and relevant C++ programming).
 - o Development of a 2D Puzzle Game for IOS Devices (Creating using Unity and relevant C# programming).
 - o Several unique 3D Models created within Blender or Maya.
 - o Personal projects created across differing software between 2021-2024.

WORK EXPERIENCE

OneAdvanced

2021 - PRESENT

Support Consultant -> Senior Support Consultant

- This position involves writing and maintaining prolog programming capable of
 processing invoices for a large number of customers used within an e-financial
 SaaS product. This requires us to examine documents and drafting the required
 programming logic to capture all data from said documents. My role includes
 keeping in regular communication with customers via Cloud Trade's ticketing
 system and through direct Microsoft Teams calls with customer representatives.
 This role provides the experience of a hybrid work environment of both working
 from home and in an office environment.
- This position requires extensive knowledge and daily use of a wide range of programming in Cloud Trade's unique coding language at many diverse levels.
 I collaborate with a small team and assist with my team's queries, alongside regularly undertaking new projects and work to aid my team wherever possible.
- I achieved a promotion to the position of Senior Support Consultant in August 2023 due to my extensive knowledge and skillset within the position. In this new position I have progressed to managing members of my team, providing both valuable guidance alongside taking on more programming challenges to assist both the team and our customers.
- I have worked on several new projects and have gained beneficial experience managing those projects, utilising new software such as PowerShell and SQL while gaining new experience with managing customer services and finally showcasing my leadership skills within the team, providing additional support to my team where required.

Echo-U August 2020-May 2021

Customer Service Representative

Zapatista May 2019 - December 2019

Retail Assistant

Co-operative Food/McColl's April 2015-August 2017

Customer Service Assistant

British Heart Foundation November 2013-February 2015

Voluntary Customer Service Assistant